Stefan Stadler

Software Engineer

Profile

I am a passionate software engineer that has decisive impact on state of the art software solutions for worldknown brands. In the last 6 years my main focus has been on migrating monolithic structures to single-page cloud native applications in Java, Typescript and Go.

I have worked in a variety of projects ranging from embedded software development to cloud services utilizing the technology that fits best. My success is based on constant learning and a high quality level including structured architectural decisions and test driven development.

Employment History

Software Engineer at Collaboration Factory, Munich

April 2019 — Present

- implemented a fully functional cloud solution consisting of a Kubernetes Operator and Terraform infrastructure setup in AWS
- developed an Angular 14 Frontend SDK that enables rapid development within the cplace software solution for internal, partner and customer developers
- introduced API first design principles, test driven development and state of the art tech stack
- migrated core Backend APIs and Frontend components to latest Angular and Springboot framework

The results of my work are seen daily by thousands of clients at world reknown OEMs in the automotive and pharmaceutical branch (and others).

Built a single family house at Selfemployed, Pfaffenhofen

December 2018 — March 2019

Built a single family house with 180 m² and smart home which is largely energy independent (Solar panels, Heat Pump, Battery)

Software Engineer at FTAPI Software GmbH, Munich

March 2017 — November 2018

- implemented a new reporting engine for FTAPI admins that collects and integrates vast datasets to intuitively readable summaries
- developed FTAPI Secu Forms as a greenfield project from scratch (Vue.js, Springboot, Docker, Jenkins CI environment with continuous e2e testing and deployment)

Work and Travel Eastern Europe at Selfemployed

April 2016 — February 2017

Details

017670826640

stadler.stefan3@gmail.com

Skills

Git

Docker

Java

Kubernetes

Go

Angular

Vue

Spring

AWS

Worked in social projects e.g. lighthouserelief that helps refugees on the island of Lesbos.

Software Engineer at ESG, Munich

February 2015 — March 2016

- -implemented a lightweight backend server on a Raspberry Pi that allows to demonstrate car functionalities (seat-heating, lights etc.) on mobile devices during exhibitions
- fully automated a code analysis engine for vehicle diagnostics code that reduced the time effort by 95%

Software Engineer at Bertrandt, Ingolstadt

January 2014 — January 2015

- implemented library functions for a hardware in the loop test framework that is essential to get street licenses for the latest car prototypes
- increased test bench efficiency by 30% for the control units Electronic Stability Program (ESP) and Electronic Brake Force Amplifier (EBKV)

Work and Travel Australia and East Asia at Selfemployed

October 2012 — December 2013

Work and Travel in Australia and East Asia

Software Engineer at Institute of Applied Sciences Ingolstadt, Ingolstadt

February 2011 — February 2012

- implemented algorithms for image processing and object detection in C++ (using OpenCV library, Kinect and CUDA)
- designed filters for noice reduction (e.g. Gauß, Median) and edge detection (e.g. Soble, Prewitt, Laplace)
- -built a Java Client/-Server application connecting an autonomous roboter to a production database

Professional Training and Studies at Stadtwerke Ingolstadt, Ingolstadt

September 2006 — September 2011

- successfully completed an apprenticeship as electrician and winning an award for being the best in class in Bavaria
- wrote a bachelor's thesis on stability of electric grids and provisioning of charging infrastructure for electric cars

Education

Master of International Automotive Engineering, THI Ingolstadt / RMIT Melbourne, Ingolstadt

September 2011 — September 2012

Ø 1,5

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering and Information Technologies, TH Ingolstadt / Nelson Mandela Metropolitan University, Ingolstadt, Port Elizsabeth

 ${\sf September\,2007-September\,2011}$

Ø 1,8

Abitur, Gymnasium Schrobenhausen

 $September\,2004-September\,2006$

Ø 1,9

★ Scholarship at Hanns Seidel Stiftung, Munich

March 2007 — September 2012

- participated in the scholarship program of Hanns Seidel Stiftung and successfully completed various programs on leadership and political discussion (met high ranking politicians such as the bavarian secretary of the interior)